Hayln Anderson

hayln.alaine@gmail.com (608) 658-6332 Portland, OR

Summary

I have been an educator for 18 years, developing skills in managerial and director roles in various Early Childhood Education jobs.

I have a passion for learning and gaining new skills – not just with continuing education requirements, but in unrelated education pursuits (e.g. Interpersonal Neurobiology & Software Engineering).

Experience

Program Director

Tumbleweed Infant and Preschool Houses $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Portland, OR

08/2014 - Present

- Remained composed and highly professional in a fast-paced and constantly changing environment, effectively handling challenging situations and making quick, solid decisions that support the staff and community
- Managed daily operations while overseeing multiple locations to foster well-being and community among staff and families.
- Oversaw operations and provided corrective feedback to achieve daily and long-term goals, making sure we were staying within the parameters of licensing rules.
- Managed daily staff scheduling and training of new staff, stepping into various roles as needed to keep operations running smoothly.
- Facilitated and supported communication with staff, families, and the Executive Director/Owner through meetings, emails, face-to-face conversations, etc.

Childsworks Learning Center

After-Care Program Manager • Portland, OR

08/2010 - 08/2014

- · Provided ongoing direction and leadership for program operations
- Supervised program staff, managing and evaluating performance providing high-quality services to program participants.
- Oversaw staff schedules and assignments to handle programming demands.
- Created and facilitated programming
- Facilitated program growth and expansion.

Bernie's Place

Afternoon Daycare Teacher • Portland, OR

10/2005 - 08/2010

- Maintained well-controlled classrooms by clearly outlining standards and reinforcing positive behaviors.
- Engaged with children on individual basis to build positive relationships and promote learning.
- Assisted in preparation of meals and snacks to provide children with proper nutrition.
- Gathered materials and resources to prepare for lessons and activities.
- Documented behavior, development and learning of children to enable tracking history and maintain accurate records.
- Collaborated with other teachers, parents, and administrators to facilitate positive outcomes for students.

Skills

Communication skills, Time management, Computer literacy, Leadership, Multi-Tasking and Role Flexibility

Education

Backend, Frontend, and Full Stack Programming

Nucamp Coding Bootcamp • Portland, OR 04/2023 Women in Technology Scholarship

Bachelor's of Science - Education

University of Wisconsin - Madison • Madison, WI 06/2005